### Haim Behar

Haifa, Israel / 052-4405833 / hbehar@hotmail.com

Agroforestry Engineer. I develop from critical and creative reasoning driven by a passion for learning. I have a particular interest in field work. scientific research, Aggrotech, data processing and analysis. My experience includes field assistance in agro exporters, scientific research, and volunteering in organic farms in Peru and Israel. I consider myself a solution-oriented person and I enjoy challenges.

**WORK EXPERIENCE** 



### National Agricultural Innovation Program (PNIA) (February – July 2021)

Lima, Peru

Scientific researcher

- Development of a nutraceutical with antioxidant and anti-inflammatory activity made from Black Mashua (Tropaeolum tuberosum R. & P) from the province of San Román-Puno, enriched with pulp of Camú-Camú (Myrciaria dubia (H.B.K) McVaug).
- Chemical laboratory work, extractions of natural resources, measurement of bioactive compounds and antioxidant capacity using the HPLC-DAD equipment.
- Published Scientific Paper **DOI:** https://doi.org/10.15446/rfnam.v74n3.93020

Behar, H., Reategui, O., Liviac, D., Arcos, J., & Best, I. (2021). Phenolic compounds and in vitro antioxidant activity of six accessions of mashua (Tropaeolum tuberosum R. & P.) from Puno Region, Peru. Revista Facultad Nacional de Agronomía Medellín, 74(3), 9707-9714.



### Florida Blanca S.A.C (March 2020 – January 2021)

Ica, Peru

Field Assistant

Agro-export company of Asparagus and Grapes.

- I worked in the field, verified that cultural work, phytosanitary applications and fertigation, reporting to the management.
- Did statistical analysis of the data generated in the field, making Geodata Maps and improve the Weather "Davis" Application.
- Assistant Field Engineer of the 200 hectares of Asparagus.



# Category One Botanical Cannabis Medicinal (2019)

Colorado, USA

Field Assistant

Outdoor Medicinal Cannabis Growing, Located in Rye, Colorado.

- Training of crop management in all its phenological and post-harvest state (clones, vegetative, flowering, harvest, drying and curing).
- Make a manual based on the techniques and methodologies of the company.



## National Fund for Scientific and Technological Development (Conicyt) (2017 - 2018)

Scientific Assistants

Lima. Perú

Morphological and genetic characterization of the genus Vanilla in Peru. -Funded by CONICYT and the Southern Scientific University

- Research assistant of Dr. John Janovec (https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=P1dxkbYAAAAJ&hl=en&oi=ao) we went to wetland ecosystems and looking for Vanilla Species in Ucavali, Peru.
- A new species of Vanilla was discovered from Peru (Vanilla yanesha).

### **EDUCATION**

Southern Scientific University (2013 - 2018)

Lima. Perú

BSc in Agroforestry Engineering

**SKILLS** 

Language: Native in Spanish; Fluent in English, Intermediate Hebrew.

Technical: Proficient in Python, SQL, Advance Excel, Mailchimp, Clouds Programs, HTML, CSC, Photoshop.

**Social:** Creative, Leadership, Teamwork, Positive attitude, Field Work.

Interests: Aggrotech, Organic Farms, Medical Cannabis, Data Analyst. App Development

#### **VOLUNTARY EXPERIENCE**

Permaculture Voluntaries: Making Compost, Biochar, Bio Buildings, Recycling, Seed Databases, Agroforestry Systems. In: IMGUARDIAN https://www.imguardian.org/ (2021), Tierra Langla www.tierralangla.pe (2017), INKATERRA https://www.inkaterra.com/ (2016), Ecological Social Project (ASPRIDEQ) https://www.manuparkvolunteer.com (2015) and Kibutz Ein Gev https://www.eingev.com/ (2012).